Welcome back to AM Northwest. Our first guest is
a wealth of information when it comes to vintage
treasures and knowing what they're worth. Here
to share an incredible music collection along
with some helpful tips, we welcome back antique
appraiser Gary Germer. Great to see you.
You too,
Helen. Thanks for having me back. You
bet. Okay, this is an amazing collection.
You're doing an
estate sale, so this is kind of one of the
things, types of things you run across.
Well, you never
know when they asked me to come, do I
have a story for it? And I said, boy,
do I have a story.
There's an estate we're working on. Over
5,000 albums and all kinds of music.
It's an amazing,
he was an audiophile. Everything else
was junk, but the audio was really great.
And it was,
so I've been immersed in this on how to do it.
And it's a big deal. People are collecting a
lot
of vinyl. Young kids will collect a lot of
vinyl. Right, they're back collecting vinyl now,
yeah.
And, you know, we all have ours from
when we were kids, you know. Do you have,
something that's worth money? And I want to
tell you what I'm doing to research all of this.
Okay. So let's talk, let's start with
this. Down in here? Well, this is,
these three kind of go
together. What, first thing I want to say is
condition means a lot. So when you want to study,
condition means a lot. And that's the first thing
you want to look, you might have a rare album.
It's like a rare book. If it's in, if it's torn
up and missing pages, it's not worth anything.
Same thing with your album. Okay. And then, and
so I wanted to use this as an illustration of
this.
This album here, these three are,
this is the Beatles yesterday and
today, and this is the infamous,
Capitol Records, it's the infamous Butcher
cover, they called it. Oh, I remember this.
Okay.
And this, this is kind of a legend in
the music business, the Butcher cover.
And they, they produced this album.
They got so much blowback and anger people,
because in 1966, this was incredibly shocking,
you know.
Yeah, yeah, it was. Squid Game
hadn't come out yet, so, you know.
So, it, it was so shocking, they had to pull it.
So they pulled it. After a few weeks of having
it,
they got it out for sale. And then they papered
over it what they called the trunk cover.
And that, I didn't, of all the books, I couldn't
find one, but they had this poster of one.
Okay. So if you look here, it's just, if you
look at this part here, would be the cover.
Okay. And it's Paul sitting in a trunk
and the guys are standing around.
And they papered over that, over, over
this, with that, because the new cover,
and then they would produce,
yesterday and today, it was produced within,
with the trunk cover from then on out.
Oh, wow.
So then, you know, well, how do I
know I have one that's papered over?
If you look on the album here, Ringo on this
side over here, well, I'm doing it backwards,
on this, yeah,
Ringo here has this V, you
can see the obvious shirt.
Right.
And on the one that's papered over,
it bleeds through, you can see the V.
So if you get one that's, that looks
like that, the trunk cover, and it's,
you have the number two.
And so, and then that makes,
that makes more sense.
So then, some people then,
oh, I've got the number one.
Right.
And so they peel it off,
which is what this is.
This actually is.
Right.
This would have been the number two, except
somebody peeled off, and that's why it's all scraped
up.
And it looks like it's
been through the war.
But, well, let's say, what could you
get for this if you wanted to sell it?
If this was in mint condition, the original,
they sell anywhere from $10,000 to $30,000.
Whoa.
And you can find them like that, and the highest
is $150,000 for one, but that was owned by
John Lennon.
Okay.
So that's a whole different subject.
Yeah.
But $30,000.
Okay.
So you could get a little bit more.
If you have the number two that's been
papered over, it's worth $5,000 to $10,000.
And whoever peeled this one off
turned it into a $200 to $300 record.
Oh, gotcha.
Okay.
So if you find them, but that,
and you'll find fakes out there.
Yeah.
And, you know, that aren't real.
You'll also find promotional things, like this
one has it on there, but that was a 1980s fan
club only.
Oh.
But still, it's only a few,
excuse me, a few hundred dollars.
Okay.
Now, let's talk about this one right here.
This is my, I, this is
probably my favorite.
One of them is the Beatles versus Don Ho.
I mean, who wouldn't want to spend
their evening listening to that?
I love it.
Yes.
And there's a Beatles versus, and these
oddities that you find, the Beatles were,
of course, had Apple Records,
Capital Records was their label.
But they would do things on
the BBC, network television.
Right.
That was not copyrighted.
They could take it off and they made, other
people would take that, buy it from like the BBC
and make these oddities.
Wow.
Oddity pieces.
Right.
And, like this one here is one that
was made and it's from the BBC.
It's a terrible recording.
Somebody stood in front of
a speaker and recorded it.
But it is a true collector's item.
This one's sealed.
Each one came with a different photograph and a
little clip of a nine millimeter film that came
from the Beatles.
Wow.
And, but it's fun.
It's interesting.
You have to really be a serious
Beatle maniac to want this.
To want to buy it.
So it's a hundred dollar record.
Okay.
This guy.
Beatles at the beach.
Beatles, there's a whole
Beatles at the Beeb.
Which was.
Oh, Beeb.
I thought you said beach.
Okay.
Beatles at the.
And that's a club in England
before they were famous.
They had recorded it and then
they were brought out later.
Okay.
Another thing you want to look at for
records sometimes are colored records.
That the vinyl itself, like this blue one.
Mm-hmm.
And you'll find it with a
lot of different artists.
Yeah.
Not just the Beatles.
If you find a colored album, double
check and make sure it's any good.
And that is the incredible, and
that's probably a $200 record.
Okay.
If you want to research
them, I wanted to get this.
This is the takeaway for folks.
Yes.
Discogs is the grand prize.
It's the granddaddy
website you want to use.
You know, the internet's going to
put me out of business in five years.
So everybody can just scan
it and look on the internet.
But Discogs, that's D-I-S-C-O-G,
disc and catalog together.
Right, that makes sense.
And they have probably every record that's
ever made and you can get information about it.
And they have prices as well.
There's another site called Popsike.
P-O-P-S-I-K-E-S.
No, S. P-O-P-S-I-K-E.com.
And it's a little bit better for pricing.
Mm-hmm.
Because it's more current pricing.
Right.
eBay, you can find a snapshot of
what's sold in the last few months.
Once you've started, but Discogs will help
you figure out exactly what it is you have
and from there you can
find out what it's worth.
Okay.
And then the little cardboard.
The cardboard.
So these were things they brought
just to kind of balance the table out.
But anything Beatles related has a value.
You should check into it.
Yeah.
These were promotional things obviously
for record stores and shops to put up.
Sure.
And you can find them around.
And they started printing them
again just to sell them as is.
$30 on that.
Yeah.
The posters, 1965.
And it's David, I'm assuming
Steve Sacks is the artist.
These were the blacklight ones.
Oh.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah.
Remember blacklight posters?
Yeah, blacklight posters,
$200, $300 for those.
Wow.
All right.
Gary, thank you very much.
You bet.
Love it.
All right.